hello I'm your host David Bernard
today's conversation is shorter than
usual and will be featured in Revenue
cats state of subscription apps report
each episode in this series we'll
explore one crucial metric and share
actionable insights from Top
subscription app operators with me today
Shane Lee Solutions architect at absf on
the podcast I talk with Shane about the
state of major acquisition channels in
2025 how improved measurement is
increasing confidence in ad spend and
why Reddit much be your next top
performing user acquisition Channel hey
Shane thanks so much for joining me on
the podcast today thanks David thanks
for having us uh very excited to join
I'm my name is Shane I'm a Solutions
architect here at apps flyer typically
work on pre-sales side of things but I
work on a variety of clients including
subscription apps itself of all sizes so
super happy to to join and uh give
insights itself awesome so I did want to
talk through what you're seeing and I
think working at apps you do have a
really unique perspective on the
industry I mean y'all work with tens of
thousands of apps across all different
verticals and see like what's working
what's not working you get to see a lot
of data that probably few people in the
industry get to see you get to like work
Hands-On with a lot of people in the
industry who get those unique
perspectives I think few folks in the
industry get so yeah super excited to
kind of dive into what's working today
2025 with acquisition for subscription
apps and so I wanted to go through all
the major channels but let's just kick
it off with like an overview what's
going on with user acquisition today
what's working what's not in the past
several years on iOS signal loss has
been the biggest kind of challenge
itself so how do we know that a ad is
actually driving subscriptions itself so
as with iOS with SK ad Network we've got
limited measurement windows so
essentially in order to do measurement
we have to be very creative with how we
do this measurement itself today Android
is business as usual for iOS there's
several new developments in 2024 and
which we can also take advantage of in
in 2025 let's go through just Channel by
Channel and like what's working what's
not so Apple search ads I mean this is
kind of like the starter kit of what I
and you know many people recommend like
if you're not at least starting with
search ads you're probably leaving money
on the table so what do you see working
in search ads and then anything new or
different these past couple years
typically search chats are still working
pretty well any measurement partner is
still getting reports of the keyword
data so what are you buying Etc where
are your placements you're still able to
lifetime value or LTB these users so
it's easy to see a user coming in on
Apple search ads and then ultimately did
they subscribe did they cancel did they
renew so these are all signals that
still were on Apple search ads itself
one thing that did change super recently
so I imagine you and the team are still
kind of sorting through exactly how this
is going to to impact things but I know
Apple did change viewr attribution with
apple search ads I don't even fully
understand it but has somebody who does
this day and day out maybe you can
explain it to me and the audience a
little better and like what it will and
won't impact moving forward let's do a
little bit of historical as well so
historically with apple search ads we
were able to get clickthrough
attribution or essentially as long as
someone's clicked on the ad and we do
attribution with them by way of their
tokens we do have the ability to
attribute on these clicks so very
recently Apple search ads announced that
they are also doing viewr attributions
and essentially what that means is let's
say they've searched for a keyword and
they've seen promotion or seen the ad
itself essentially What's Happening Here
is they're able to also tell us that hey
there was a viewr attribution for this
particular device and how that's going
to help is even though they saw a
keyword that they searched on even
though they didn't click on it we're
able to still report on the fact that
there was a view of that ad itself gocha
is that going to like over attribute to
search ads like is that I think I saw a
few people on Twitter commenting on
maybe over attribution or is that just
an additional signal that you're going
to be able to like sort differently than
the click-through attributions our
comment here or my comment here is going
to be more that they are leveling the
playing field So Meta Tik Tok Google all
do viewr attributions today it was
something that was asked for by various
advertisers itself but now they able to
see the performance of the viewr
attributions regardless you're still
able to filter these within the
dashboard so you see viewrs and you see
click-throughs anyways so I would not
call that overattribution I would
essentially say that it's an additional
signal itself cool yeah yeah so it
sounds like more helpful than anything
else it it's great to see apple evolving
on things I mean I think there's many
fronts where we would hope Apple and
Google will continue evolving let's move
on to some of the bigger networks Tik
Tok has been in the news a ton this year
and a ton of people are are finding more
success I mean I feel like it's really
growing if you use your acquisition
Channel not just for trying to go viral
and Organics but also actually you know
running campaigns on Tik Tok What do you
see going on in Tik Tok so for 2024
we'll talk about 2025 in a second here
2024 there was there were quite a lot of
developments itself number one they
became a uh self-reporting or self-
attributing network so essentially
they're responding back to us with hey
we did see attribution itself typically
when happens with a self-reporting
network there's a device ID that needs
to be transmitted iOS the issue there is
that you now have to prompt on both
sides so essentially we have signal loss
there for 2024 going into 2025 we now
have them as a advanced srn so
essentially what happens here is there
are additional signals that are sent
over to them to make attribution itself
so we're seeing quite a big lift in
terms of attribution through that method
essentially Tik Tok was the first one
that did it with us following suit
Snapchat also did that with us and then
meta as well and hopefully Google pretty
soon but essentially with this with the
advanced srns we are starting to get
more signals Itself by sending
additional parameters over for
attribution gotcha and and so you
mentioned that getting those additional
signals is helping drive more efficient
spend and being able to to get the
signal quicker and more accurate from
that srn integration correct we're
getting the signals better quicker
because we're not relying on scans
24-hour or delay mechanism in addition
you're able to LTB the users so we do
abide by any of the user data retention
policies they all have different
retention policies but you're able to
LTV the users for a subscription app
what that means is now we could see that
hey they did subscribe 7 days later and
then they did renew a month two month
three month four for instance yeah I
imagine that's super helpful moving on
to meta I I feel like meta is seems like
the network that is most quickly and
most effectively recovered from ATT over
the past few years and I just hear so
many apps who are doing well on meta
these days that the the signals are
getting stronger the algorithms like
figuring it out what are yall seeing on
your end as far as the effectiveness of
a meta and any changes to that on the
meta and uh itself they are the they are
one of the larger ones um aside from
Google uh itself so ESS entally what
we're seeing here is just more
attribution methods there are web to app
plays itself so sometimes advertisers do
send them to a web landing page first
and then ultimately into their app for a
subscription sometimes they do a
subscription first and then into the app
and then they do send them into the app
itself so there's various methods of
doing this outside of scan you could
still run SK ad network with skad
network you do have that limited window
itself so we do see advertisers taking
advantage of multiple ways of doing this
so just to recap it is app install
campaigns with advanced srns in 2025
that's a very big signal recovery there
still are web to app plays with meta
itself so essentially sending them to a
web landing page and then ultimately
converting and in parallel there's still
skad Network that can be ran as well
probably should be a completely separate
topic but let's going on with scan is it
getting more effective you know it does
seem like more of the big networks are
adopting it yeah tell me about what
you're seeing work and not work as far
as scan goes scan skad Network we are
seeing a lot of networks coming on it's
over 100 now itself usually the larger
ones meta Google Tik Tok for instance
essentially that's still the
deterministic way of getting hey where
did your users come from the limitations
here are just going to be that you're
only able to measure up to a certain
amount of time so networks on scan 3
you're able to measure 48 Hours
essentially of data and then for
networks on scan 4 you're able to
measure up to 35 days of data however on
your second and third postbacks what's
happening there is you have less
Fidelity so for subscription app it
might be did they subscribe or not
there's not much more details that can
be put into those post backs do you see
any networks where that 35-day window
does make a meaningful difference like
does that first renewal on a monthly or
continued engagement does that get fed
back into the algorithm in a way that
actually helps better train the
algorithms or is it kind of one of those
like nice to have but maybe doesn't
actually impact things for the larger
networks we have not seen them using
that signal on skad network we do see it
on our dashboard we do see performance
itself but we haven't seen that actually
fed into the algorithms possibly due to
the fact that when you are looking for
signals Downstream there are privacy
thresholds itself so you don't fully
have accurate like subscription data you
have very accurate install data so users
did come from a particular Network
however when it actually comes to did
they subscribe you could be missing 10%
of that traffic we do have dashboards
that show that with a null conversion
rate however that is something that's
still an issue today with desk ad
network has the industry kind of
solidified around particular best
practices or schema around scans were
any tips about you know apps trying to
use scan it hasn't been a standard
around a template it's still been here
are six bits or 63 conversion values
let's configure that where measurement
Partners come into play here is that we
make it easy to actually configure those
itself so you can see within at least
within apps fers UI you have the ability
to configure do we want to measure
Revenue do we want to measure just the
event do we want to measure a funnel Etc
so instead of having Developers to
figure this out essentially we're having
a marketer come into marketer SL
Advertiser come into our UI and
essentially configure that in our
conversion Studio itself well moving on
to the next kind of big player in the
space Google I know Google's actually
been making a lot of moves the last
couple of years so tell me about what's
working with Google probably the biggest
thing that Google's done in the last
year from a attribution perspective is
that YouTube now serves an at prompt
very exciting for us because
historically Google did not do any
prompting so we're not able to any
measurement Partners not able to make
measurement with Google using
traditional methods and reason for that
is there's no device ID on the Google
side now that YouTube has it that's been
a huge Advantage we are now starting to
see attributions to Google or to YouTube
itself and you're able to get the same
signal so essentially if we do
attribution you're able to lifetime
value the users itself
very cool what kind of opt-in rates are
you seeing I know yall kind of share
data and it's been cool I've seen a few
reports here and there over the years of
opt-in rates and double opt-in rates but
is it meaningful and I guess even if the
percentage is low you at least have kind
of like a sample to help inform other
decisions but what are you seeing as far
as opting rates and how that affects
efficiency so couple things that we
typically advise is showing the prompt
opt-in rates itself it can be anywhere
from somewhere below 10% to 50 to 60%
depending on app we have seen really
high acceptance rates on certain apps
itself so we would still recommend
prompting and ultimately it's another
data point that you are able to capture
and possibly reuse so if you're using
maybe you might be doing re-engagement
at some point in the future so that
would be another signal that you could
send over to those networks to re-engage
this this user so we've talked about
kind of the three biggest players in the
space I mean putting aside Apple search
ads and Google Play ads which Google
Play ads run through Google anyway but
with those three biggest networks Tik
Tok meta and Google are you seeing any
particular trends of like increasing
spend on Google versus meta or Tik Tok
versus Google any Trends in kind of
shifts of spend or apps being able to
scale on one network but not another
we're just seeing overall more spend
going into all three itself so it's nice
to see and the reason why is because now
they're a little bit more confident in
terms of hey is this actually driving
performance when iOS 14 first came out
spend was held back right because even
though you put money in they don't know
is it driving results itself so now 2024
20125 with additional data points we now
are seeing advertisers invest a little
bit more confidently itself yeah that
makes sense as you're more able to more
confidently attribute that spend of
course you're going to spend more so it
makes a lot of sense and it's it's
interesting to hear that you're seeing
that just across the board versus like
any one network kind of running away
with kind of sherff Bend Reddit is
another kind of interesting topic I mean
I don't hear a lot of apps talking about
it but it feels like that could be
another huge opportunity and maybe you
know between Reddit snap and maybe
there's a few other places any thoughts
on on some of these smaller networks
where there might actually be some kind
of Arbitrage and opportunity to spend
where maybe others are overlooking so
Reddit has pretty much kickstarted their
ad Network this year so they spent a lot
more time on it particularly app install
campaigns so they've grown quite a bit
they became srn in terms of doing
attribution they are investing pretty
heavily in that they have a large user
base so it's definitely one of those
networks that are up and cominging and
something that should be considered for
subscription apps I mean people are
going in there they're reading you know
the subreddit itself they're allowing
for promotions on those subreddits and
measurement with a measurement partner
you're going to be able to see was that
an effective spin so pulling all this
together got a lot of different channels
a lot of opportunity but you know folks
listening to this podcast got to figure
out like where do we spend money how do
we spend money what are the tactics that
we need to be thinking about to help
drive that efficiency so any kind of
specific advice for folks as they kind
of navigate those Waters I think the
important part here is going going to be
measurement overall itself so having a
place where you're able to see that
performance in an unbiased way so
essentially we want to be able to
compare meta with Google with Tik Tok we
also want to be able to see your
influencers or your programmatic buys
Etc so having all that in one place is
very important also any re-engagement
like let's just say you acquire these
users but they haven't made that
subscription maybe there's an email push
that gets sent out to them maybe they're
re-engaged on another network but those
are also important tactics just to make
sure that we first acquire the user and
then we get them into a subscription
itself any other top tips especially for
subscription apps which is going to be
the majority of our listeners to make
sure that you're driving that ad spin
effectively probably the biggest one is
just to make sure that the data
pipelines are set up so essentially
having a measurement a mobile
measurement partner SDK eventally that
will help us track the installs itself
having a good pipeline for how to notify
that a subscription was actually done
back into this measurement partner
reason for that is we need to
effectively know where did that user
come from and did they actually convert
or did they actually subscribe so
typically here we see trial starts and
then subscription converted we do also
want to monitor channels where
subscribers are churning as well so
those are all effective signals but
essentially the biggest tip here is to
make sure that we have that data
pipeline set up so you're able to see
this measurement end to end so where did
they come from did they actually
subscribe and is there a particular
channel that maybe we should defocus
because a majority of the users are
churning itself yeah I mean it's a Hu
huge problem and we've talked about this
a lot on the podcast in in other ways
but sometimes you'll drive a campaign
where it looks amazing and like free
trial starts are off the charts and then
people are canceling that trial so
having that data pipeline set up well so
that you see if a channel is driving
those low intent users who are just
trying to use your free trial and are
actually intending to subscribe it's
just so important to get that
measurement piece right is to to have
that data fed in there all right well as
we wrapping up anything else you wanted
to share that's largely it just wanted
to mention appflyer is the leading
mobile measurement partner we're in most
majority of the apps out there today so
definitely if you want to learn more hit
us up at apps.com
and we'd be happy to to dive into
details itself all awesome well thanks
for joining me today really appreciate
how much data apps fer does share with
the industry you know you'll regularly
share reports and blog posts and part of
the reason we're doing this podcast is
that y'all are sharing some data that's
going to go into Revenue cast state of
subscription apps report so definitely
worth checking that out if you're
listening to the podcast and and haven't
seen the report yet checking out that
data it's going to be really interesting
and then keeping an eye on on what apps
shares make sure you're paying attention
to trend in the industry and stuff like
that so do appreciate apps sharing the
way it does thank you so much David
thank you for having us lovely being on
the podcast with with you
all thanks so much for listening if you
have a minute please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player you can
also stop by chat. subclub do.com to
join our private community
[Music]